Cooper Howlett

Phone number - 808-495-3938

Email address - Howlettman@gmail.com

Address – 9317 NE SouthBeach Drive, Bainbridge Island, WA, 98110

Profile:

Energetic and dependable engineer with a wide range of experience in enterprise software engineering, web-development, and scientific computing. I have strong communication skills as well as practiced leadership skills with an extensive background in software engineering.

Skills:

- Software engineering experience with Python, C, and C++, along with experience in GUI development.
- Web development experience with JavaScript, NodeJS, Ajax, Python-Flask, PHP, HTML5, CSS, and restful methodology.
- Image recognition and processing, computer vision, and mathematical modeling with low signal to noise ratio data.

Education:

University of Hawaii Hilo

Hilo, Hawaii

Bachelor of Arts in Physics, GPA: 3.78/4.0

2015 to 2018

- Two years of applied physics experience including coursework and projects as well as research in computational physics using Python and Mathematica, as well as software projects using C and C++.
- Course and lab experience in Computational Physics, Electromagnetics, Condensed Matter/Solid State Physics, Fluid Dynamics, Optics, Thermodynamics, Quantum Mechanics, Electrical Engineering, and Classical Mechanics.

Work Experience:

Mantle

Remote, Hawaii

Consultant, Part-Time

June 2019 to Current

- Developed web-services build using JavaScript, NodeJS, PHP, and HTML5.
- Improved and maintained WordPress based client websites.

NivamIT Inc

Remote, Virginia

Information Technology Specialist, Full-Time

October 2018 to Current

- Heavy use of Python with Flask, GDAL/OGR, numpy, tkinter, and ArcGIS/ArcPY packages.
- Transition FEMA-HAZUS flood-modeling scripts from licensed ArcGIS software to open-source QGIS systems.
- Development of GUI based enterprise software for HAZUS flood modeling.
- Built a restful web-service using Flask interface with JavaScript, PHP, and HTML5.

Pacific Disaster Center

Remote, Hawaii

Jr Disaster Risk Analyst, Part-Time

March 2018 to Current

Software Engineering Intern in Applied Sciences, Part-Time

June 2018 to February 2019

- Heavy use of Python with ArcGIS/ArcPY, numpy, and MySQL for databases, as well as Powershell for automation.
- Created automated and GUI based software simulation for testing hazard models with
- Tasks included debugging, documenting, and optimizing automated disaster models in Python.
- Developed restful web-service in Flask using Python, PHP, and HTML5 for automated web-based disaster models.

National Solar Observatory

Pukalani, Hawaii

Research Assistant, Part-Time

October 2018 to August 2019

- Heavy use of Python with numpy, sunpy, astropy, OpenCV, and scikit.
- Designed and created models for analysis of granulation of sunspots from NASA telescope data.
- Analyzed and Digitized historical sunspot telescope data by using image recognition techniques.

Projects:

- Open-Source Flood Modeling: Built in Python with GDAL, numpy, pandas, geopandas. Remade without use of expensive licensed software. Includes intuitive dynamic GUI. Increased speed by 20 times vs original: github.com/nhrap-dev/FAST
- Online Checkers Game: Based in JavaScript and PHP with HTML5 canvas for the interface and AJAX for live playing: github.com/cbhowlett/JSCheckers